

I'm a seasoned digital craftsman, with over 20 years of experience as a designer, web developer, UX practitioner, video producer, and animator. I'm an intensely curious "expert generalist" who loves teaching and learning new skills.

Skills

UX & Product Design

When considering design solutions, I strive to understand the total problem.

I help teams clarify and prioritize business goals, strategy, and online mediums through proven UX disciplines, research, content strategy, written and visual explorations, design artifacts and prototypes. I strive to use the right UX tool (such as a card sort or journey map) and just the right level of visual fidelity (using tools like paper prototyping, Invision, Axure, and UXPin) to convey the solution effectively as fast as possible. Stickies & whiteboards are my constant companions.

UX Disciplines: Relative Strengths*



*Nick Finck at Amazon shared <u>this model</u> for UX team strength assessment.

Web & Mobile Design & Development

I deliver responsive, mobile-ready websites, publishing workflows and training. I use Statamic, Expression Engine and Wordpress CMS; front-end development using HTML5, CSS3/SASS using build systems like Grunt, Gulp, and Node.js. I've created hybrid mobile apps with PhoneGap and Mobile Roadie, and custom-built pattern libraries to empower internal teams.

Proficient in HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Jade, Markdown, and comfortable with PHP & Javascript.

Git workflow, SSH, web fonts, responsive imagery, & SVG applications.

Video & Motion Graphics

Cinematography, editing, color grading and post-production, editing, motion graphics & animation. Experience in high-volume workflow design, training, and asset management. Extensive mobile production experience in challenging environments in the US, Caribbean, and Africa.

I'm a veteran of high-stakes live events, from live web meetings, corporate and donor events, to large outdoor festivals (some with over 100,000 in attendance). I learned to work very fast under intense pressure.

After Effects, nodal compositors, Premiere, Flash, Davinci Resolve, Final Cut Pro X, Motion, Keynote, CatDV, ProPresenter, Quartz Composer.

DSLR filmmaking, sound & music editing.

Design & Photography

My journey began with the disciplines of design: art direction & branding development in print, digital, and motion. Photography is close to my heart; in addition to teaching photo workshops and photojournalism work, I continue to shoot professionally when time permits.

Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch, OmniGraffle, LightRoom.

Presentation design, public speaking, and training

A true craftsman is one who teaches and mentors others. One of my true passions is educating, training, and casting vision among clients, users and team members.

Keynote, ProPresenter, endless practice



Experience

HealthSparq

Senior User Experience Designer

October 2013 – Present

At HealthSparg, I design & help develop the visual layer for our front-end team. I play the role of a general-purpose UX designer, and so may be used at any stage in design or development, from discovery to design studios, through wireframing, prototyping, and front-end coding. I design internal tools like our pattern library, designed our new company website, and conduct design education & training.

Luis Palau Association

Video & Web Producer

February 2006 – July 2013 (7 years 6 months)

Web & mobile development, user experience design, all aspects of video & motion graphics production, presentation design, event production, event photography, art direction, social media marketing.

R. Allan White Design & Multimedia

Freelance Digital Designer

June 2001 – February 2006 (4 years 9 months)

Produced and designed high-quality print, web, Flash, multimedia and video work for a variety of clients, agencies, and industries, including HP, Intel, Epicor, EMI Music, Primavera Systems, Universal Studios, Verve Records, and Copper Mountain Resorts.

Strobeck Design, Inc.

Rich Media Director

December 2001 – February 2003 (2 years)

Directed, planned, budgeted and engineered all types of audio, video, web and interactive projects. Performed high-level content development, IA, writing and editing.

White Horse

Interactive Art Director

March 1998 – February 2001 (3 years)

Designed and directed cutting-edge media products for web, kiosk and CD. Created workflows and established asset-management strategies. Trained other team members in the latest tools & technologies.

Education

Harding University

BFA, Graphic Design

August 1991 - December 1994

Colorado State University

August 1990 – June 1991



Need a flexible, seasoned, and skilled UX designer who can see the big picture?

Contact me today.